Jamie Peterson

Software Developer

An enthusiastic software developer with experience building web-based applications for Fortune 500 and Silicon Valley tech companies. Currently focused on web development, but is constantly furthering skills in relevant fields including project management, cloud computing, and user experience.



hire@jamiepeterson.me



(586) 764 - 0500



Ann Arbor, MI



jamiepeterson.me

in

linkedin.com/in/jamie-peterson



github.com/jpeter61

KEY SKILLS

Java

Agile

Spring Framework

SQL

Design Patterns

Empathy

Flexibility

Maven

Unit Testing

Communication

Kubernetes

Accountable

INTERESTS

Cloud Computing

Web Development

Artificial Intelligence

Android Development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Nexient

05/2018 - Present

Developer for various clients building high-quality software and systems while integrating into existing teams

- Migrating core platform of client's application to Kubernetes hosted on Amazon Web Services
- Dockerizing existing Java micro-services
- Developed a Java/Spring back-end for client's internal tool with a MVP in 2 weeks
- Re-designed client's SQL database greatly reducing query time
- Built Angular 6 front-end application for internal tool and responsible for over 50% of unit tests
- Increased code quality and test coverage for internal Java/Spring micro-services

Team Lead

The Honors College at EMU

12/2017 - 04/2018

Led a small team of student developers developing PHP web-applications

- Added 2 applications to the team's portfolio
- Oversaw the development and maintenance of 5 projects
- Communicated with product owners and generated requirements

Computing Fellow

The Honors College at EMU

01/2017 - 12/2017

Part of a small team developing PHP web-applications

- Participated in each step of the development process
- Created code and documentation standards
- Presented projects to 2 academic conferences

CERTIFICATION

Oracle Java SE 8 Programmer I

Actively pursuing, anticipated - February 2019

EDUCATION

BS in Computer ScienceEastern Michigan University

09/2014 - 04/2018

Graduated cum laude and with University Honors